Girona, Spain

🖶 wilberquito | **in** wilberquito | ⊠ typingwil@gmail.com | 🛭 (+34) 698-40-53-59 | 💣 wilberquito.github.io

"The best way to predict the future is to create it."

### About Me

With more than three years of experience in IT solutions, I began my career as a Software Developer. However, I quickly transitioned to datadriven solutions, focusing on Machine Learning and statistical methods. I am also passionate about developing personal projects, including short posts, video game development, and engaging in physical sports whenever possible.

## **Education**

University of Girona GIRONA, SPAIN

MSc. in Data Science 🗞

Sep. 2023

· Studies focused on advanced skills in analyzing and deriving insights from data using statistical and machine learning methods.

**University of Girona** GIRONA, SPAIN

BEng. in Computer Science ®

Jun. 2022

· I take pride in my accomplishment of attaining excellence in the final degree project, which entailed the creation of an open-source video game.

# **Work Experience**

**Citibeats** BARCELONA, SPAIN Data Scientist Sep. 2023 - Mar. 2024

- Developed topic modeling pipelines with large language models (LLMs) such as BERT, RoBERTa and Sentence Transformers. Implemented solutions to predict topic trends and anomalies using recurrent neural networks (RNNs) and long short-term memories (LSTM).
- Enhanced prediction explainability through clustering and additional trained models, providing deeper insights into the text data.
- Developed private Python libraries, created web-hook services, and deployed trained models in private repositories.
- · Provided technical support for previous company projects, including fixing bugs, adding features, and re-fitting or fine tunning models.
- · Conducted research and implemented rapid experiments, thoroughly documenting the process for reproducibility and results.

University of Girona GIRONA, SPAIN

Associate Assistant Professor

Feb. 2023 - Aug. 2023

 My responsibilities included overseeing lab sessions in order to instruct students in functional and logic programming, correct lab projects, and supervise exams.

**Accenture SL** GIRONA, SPAIN

Computer Vision Research

Dec. 2022 - Aug. 2023

 Developed and open-sourced a Computer-Aided Diagnosis (CAD) platform using Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) for detecting melanoma.

#### **Nexus Geographics**

GIRONA, SPAIN

Data Engineer

Sep. 2021 - Sep. 2022

- · Significantly contributed to the development of a concurrent framework designed to capture, map, and store data from diverse sources.
- · Created and manteined API micro-services to injest and serve data. Ensuring data consistency across multiple databases.
- Designed and developed interactive web applications to visualize on-demand and streaming data.
- Provided training to new team members on the primary technologies utilized in the projects and offered problem-solving support.

WILBER BERMEO OUITO · CURRICULUM VITAE

NexTReT Girona, Spain

Software Engineer Abr. 2020 - Sep. 2021

- Designed and developed a wide range of Restful APIs.
- Created interactive web applications for the healthcare sector, taking responsibility for building modules including authentication, hospital bed administration, external hospital services, and more.

## Tech Skills

**Programming Languages** Python, R, Haskell, Scala, Java, JS, C++, and more

ML & Data Tools PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, Hugging Face, Pandas, SQL, Kafka, and more

MLOps / DevOps MLFlow, W&B, Docker, GitHub Actions, and Git

**Frameworks** FastAPI, Flask, Spring Boot, Svelte, Angular, and more **Workflow** Jupyter Notebook, Neovim, Linux, GitHub and GitLab

**Cloud** AWS stack and Google Colab

## Other Skills of Interest

**Languages** English (C1), Spanish (Native), Catalan (Bilingual)

**Driver's License** B

## **Certificates**

2023 Prevention & Emergency Management, Co-funded by the Erasmus+ Programme of the European Union

2022 Spark and Python for Big Data with PySpark, Udemy

2022 Advanced Machine Learning, Kaggle

2022 Advanced SQL, Kaggle

2021 Advanced Functional Programming (FP), University of Helsinki

## References\_

PROF. DR. MATEU VILLARET SPROFESSOR AT UNIVERSITY OF GIRONA MATEU.VILLARET@UDG.EDU

PROF. DR. GUSTAVO PATOW PROFESSOR AT UNIVERSITY OF GIRONA GUSTAVO.PATOW@UDG.EDU

QUIM DALMAU **S**TECH LEAD AT CITIBEATS
JDALMAUT@GMAIL.COM